Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection 1890-1970 AD.MC.002
AbuDhabi
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  - A group of men, eating and drinking outdoors. Same group of men from ref810. 6.9 x 10.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Drinking; Eating; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Food; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - A group of men, eating and drinking outdoors. Same group of men from ref809. 7.0 x 10.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Drinking; Eating; Egypt; English Writing; Fezes / Tarbouches; Food; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - A man in a suit, with a Wheeling, West Virginia pennant on the table next to him. 15.2 x 10.1 cm, 1920; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Clocks & Watches; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Wheeling, West Virginia, USA
  - A woman sitting on the back of a rattan chair. Same woman from ref 813. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, 1926; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Egypt; French Writing; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Potted Plants; Women
  - A woman standing in front of a console table. Same woman from ref812. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, 1926; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Egypt; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Potted Plants; Women
  - A man on horse back, in the desert, near the Pyramids of Giza, Egypt. Duplicate. 14.0 x 8.5 cm, 17 December 1922; Ali, K. Ghamrawy (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Deserts; English Writing; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; Horses; Men; Photographic Prints; Pyramids of Giza
  - A man on horseback wearing a pith helmet, in front of a large building (sane building as ref800). 14.2 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Horses; Men; Photographic Prints
  - A ribbon cutting ceremony. Same man from ref817, ref818, ref819 and ref820. 9.0 x 13.9 cm, Circa 1958-1971; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Audiences; Ceremonies; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits; Traditional Dress
  - A group of men walking up stairs, with a large crowd behind them. Same man from ref816, ref 818, ref819 and ref820. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Circa 1958-1971; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Audiences; Ceremonies; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Flags; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - A man addressing a crowd using a microphone. Same man from ref816, ref817, ref819 and ref820. 9.0 x 13.9 cm, Circa 1958-1971; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Audiences; Ceremonies; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Microphones; Photographic Prints
  - A group of five men listening to a speech, given by a man on a microphone. Same man from ref816, ref817, ref818 and ref820. 9.0 x 13.8 cm, Circa 1958-1971; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Audiences; Ceremonies; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Microphones; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
  - A group of men in a Chevrolet car, surrounded by a crowd of people. Same men from ref816, ref817, ref818 and ref819. 8.7 x 13.8 cm, Circa 1958-1971; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Audiences; Cars; Ceremonies; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - A young child posing on the sidewalk. 14.0 x 8.8 cm, 1 February 1953; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Streets
  - A young boy, posing in front of the Place de la Concorde, with the Luxor Obelisk and the Eiffel Tower in the background. 8.1 x 11.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Boys; Cars; Eiffel Tower, Paris, France; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Paris, France; Photographic Prints; Place de la Concorde, Paris, France
  - A large group sat at a table outdoors. 9.4 x 6.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Drinking; Eating; Egypt; Food; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Trees; Women
  - Two men sitting on a sofa, one reads a copy of Al Ahram newspaper (linked ref1067). 5.8 x 5.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Newspapers; Photographic Prints; Reading; Suits
  - A man sitting in front of a cabinet, with a fountain pen in his hand. 6.0 x 5.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Egypt; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - Four German women dancing on a stage in the garden of Villa Austria. 8.8 x 11.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Dancing; Gelatin Silver Prints; German Writing; Performance Plays; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A small family group on the stairs of Villa Austria. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Architecture; Buildings; Children; Family; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A young girl on the stairs of Villa Austria. 13.9 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Houses; Individual Portraits; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - Villa Austria. 13.6 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Architecture; Buildings; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A young girl in the garden of Villa Austria. 8.8 x 13.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Architecture; Buildings; Flowers; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A woman and a girl in the garden of Villa Austria. 8.8 x 12.1 cm, 1920; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Family Portraits; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; German Writing; Girls; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - Four dancing girls on a small stage in the garden of Villa Austria. Same girls from ref838. 8.7 x 11.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Architecture; Costumes; Dancing; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; German Writing; Girls; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A small family group standing on the stairs at the side of Villa Austria. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Architecture; Buildings; Family Portraits; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A party in the garden of Villa Austria. 6.3 x 9.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Parties; Photographic Prints
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A couple in the garden of Villa Austria. 10.4 x 5.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Architecture; Buildings; Couples; Flowers; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Men; Photographic Prints; Trees; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A group at the Pyramids of Giza. 10.6 x 8.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Archaeological Sites; Cairo, Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Men; Photographic Prints; Pyramids of Giza; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A young girl in the garden, in front of Villa Austria. 6.4 x 11.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Flowers; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Houses; Photographic Prints; Trees
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A young woman sitting in the garden of Villa Austria. 8.4 x 13.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Flowers; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - Four dancing girls on a small stage in the garden of Villa Austria. Same girls from ref831. 8.8 x 11.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Costumes; Dancing; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; German Writing; Girls; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - Women dressed as Napoleonic soldiers in the garden of Villa Austria. 9.5 x 14.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Costumes; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Military / Soldiers; Parties; Photographic Prints; Uniforms; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A woman with two young girls on the stairs of Villa Austria. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Architecture; Buildings; Family; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Houses; Maadi, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Joseph Max Lichtenstern Family Series - A woman on stage, holding a parasol at Villa Austria. 8.9 x 11.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Costumes; Fashion Accessories; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Desert Cars Series - A group of men standing in front of a sign, reading Khargeh. 5.8 x 8.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Deserts; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Kharga Oasis, Western Desert, Egypt; Men; Oases; Photographic Prints; Traditional Dress
  - Desert Cars Series - Four cars in the desert. 5.6 x 8.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Cars; Deserts; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Kharga Oasis, Western Desert, Egypt; Men; Oases; Photographic Prints
  - Desert Cars Series - A man smoking a pipe, in front of a car. 8.2 x 5.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Cars; Deserts; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Kharga Oasis, Western Desert, Egypt; Men; Oases; Photographic Prints; Smoking
  - Desert Cars Series - Two men posing in front of a car. 8.1 x 5.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Clipping from a newspaper, with a picture of a man with a large handle bar mustache. 13.7 x 8.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Mustaches; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers; Photographic Prints
  - Series I - A group of men and boys sat at a restaurant outdoors. 13.9 x 9.0 cm, 20 August 1926; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Restaurants
  - Series II - A group of five men with two young boys. 8.7 x 13.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Boys; Canes/Walking Sticks; Egypt; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Series III - A group of men standing in front of a thatched building. 13.7 x 8.8 cm, 18 August 1926; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Canes/Walking Sticks; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Series IV - A group of six men sitting at a restaurant. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Traditional Dress
  - Series V - A man sitting on the beach in front of a small sailboat. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Beaches; Boats; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Seas
  - Series VI - A man standing in front of a thatched wall. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Traditional Dress
  - Series VII- A group of nine men. 9.0 x 13.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Canes/Walking Sticks; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - Series - A woman standing next to a pond with swans, in Hyde Park, London. 6.0 x 8.4 cm, March 1938; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Arabic Writing; Birds; English Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; London, England; Parks; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Series - A group standing by a car on the road. 6.3 x 8.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Bicycles; Cars; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Streets; Women
  - Series - A man and a boy, sitting on the front of a car. 6.3 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Boys; Buildings; Cars; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Series - A woman and a boy wearing glasses next to a car. 7.5 x 10.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Boys; Cars; Egypt; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Accident Series - A woman, with a purse, before an accident. Same woman from ref859. 13.7 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Bags; Egypt; Fashion Accessories; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Makeup; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Accident Series - A woman with scars on her face, after an accident. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Egypt; French Writing; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Greek Family Series - Two women and young girl. Same subjects from ref868. 6.3 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Egypt; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Hats; Jewellery; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Greek Family Series - Three women sitting in a park. 9.0 x 13.7 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Egypt; Fur Garments; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Hats; Parks; Photographic Prints; Restaurants; Women
  - Greek Family Series - Four children, three girls and one boy. 8.8 x 12.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Architecture; Boys; Canes/Walking Sticks; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Group Portraits; Hats; Photographic Prints
  - Greek Family Series - A group standing with a horse, chickens and dogs. 7.2 x 10.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Animals; Birds; Dogs; Egypt; Farms; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Men; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Greek Family Series - Four women sitting outdoors. 9.1 x 15.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Houses; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Greek Family Series - A group posing with a horse, chickens and dogs. 8.1 x 10.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Animals; Birds; Dogs; Egypt; Farms; Fur Garments; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Greek Family Series - A group posing in a garden. Same group from ref867. 8.1 x 10.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Greek Family Series - Two men and two women, sitting on a bench in a garden. Same group from ref866. 10.5 x 8.1 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Greek Family Series - Two women and a young girl. Same subject from ref860. 13.9 x 8.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Egypt; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Hats; Jewellery; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - Greek Family Series - A young woman in a light dress on a balcony. 14.5 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Architecture; Balcony / Terrace; Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Streets; Women
  - Egyptian Family Series - A group of men and boys in front of a bus. 7.0 x 11.8 cm, 8 March 1959; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Buses; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Egyptian Family Series - A group of men and boys posing in front of a bus. 7.0 x 11.7 cm, 8 March 1959; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Egyptian Family Series - A boy with a gun, sitting on a chair. 6.5 x 6.4 cm, 19 February 1957; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Arabic Writing; Balcony / Terrace; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - Egyptian Family Series - A boy with a gun under his arm. 6.6 x 6.4 cm, 19 February 1957; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - Egyptian Family Series - A man and a small boy next to a fountain. 6.4 x 6.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Architecture; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Fountains; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Egyptian Family Series - Two men and a boy near a fountain in a public square. 6.5 x 6.4 cm, 7 Febraury 1957; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Fountains; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Parks; Photographic Prints; Signs / Signposts
  - Egyptian Family Series - A boy holding a gun. 6.6 x 6.5 cm, 19 February 1957; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - Egyptian Family Series - A young boy and a man next to a fountain in a garden. 6.9 x 6.6 cm, 1957; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Fountains; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Insignia / Emblem; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Egyptian Family Series - Four boys leaning on a Chevrolet bus. 7.0 x 11.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Boys; Buses; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - Egyptian Family Series - Two children sitting on the sidewalk. 7.0 x 11.6 cm, 17 January 1958; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Arabic Writing; Buildings; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Streets
  - Egyptian Family Series - A young boy standing next to a sculpture. 11.7 x 7.0 cm, 1958; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Architecture; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Statues; Streets
  - Egyptian Family Series - A boy sitting between two urns in front of a statue. 7.0 x 11.7 cm, 1958; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Monuments; Photographic Prints; Statues; Streets
  - Egyptian Family Series - A man with two boys in a garden. 9.0 x 13.8 cm, 31 October 1958; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Family Portraits; Gardens; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Egyptian Family Series - A large group of school boys with teachers. 8.8 x 13.8 cm, 1951; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers
  - A young man wearing a suit and tarbouche. 10.1 x 6.9 cm, Undated; Studio M. Sabongi, Bakawy Street, Cairo, Egypt (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Boys; Cairo, Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A young boy hiding in the flowers at the park. 6.4 x 10.7 cm, 1 April 1933; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Flowers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Parks; Photographic Prints
  - A young man wearing a tarbouche. 11.3 x 6.9 cm, 11 June 1933; Studio Lazar, Ibrahimiah, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Boys; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - The city Edinburgh, Scotland from the castle. 6.9 x 8.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Castles; Edinburgh, Scotland; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
  - A young man blind folded and being forced to drink something. 4.4 x 6.6 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Greek Writing; Men; Photographic Prints; Streets; Uniforms
  - An man wearing a tarbouche. 5.6 x 4.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - Four men posing outside a building. 9.7 x 6.6 cm, 6 July 1951; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Cars; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits
  - A young child sitting on a bed with a hairbrush in its mouth. 7.5 x 10.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Beds; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - Boys playing on the beach. 7.0 x 11.9 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Bathing Suits / Swimsuits; Beaches; Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints
  - A woman holding a tray with another woman in the background. 6.0 x 8.8 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Five men eating in the desert. 6.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Deserts; Eating; Egypt; Food; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints
  - Five naval officiers on a ship. 8.8 x 6.3 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Boats; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Military / Soldiers; Navy; Photographic Prints; Ships; Uniforms
  - A family group, the man has a pipe in his mouth. 13.4 x 8.2 cm, 1 May 1956; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Children; Egypt; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Studio Photography; Women
  - The Pyramids at Giza from afar. 5.2 x 8.4 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Pyramids of Giza; Train Station / Railway Station
  - Men in suits and tarbouches in an auditorium. 6.2 x 11.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits; Theater
  - A street view of a parade, with horses and cars. 9.0 x 6.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Audiences; Carriages & Coaches; Cars; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Parades; Photographic Prints; Streets
  - Soldiers on horseback in a parade. 6.5 x 9.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Cars; Crowds; Egypt; Events / Occasions; Gelatin Silver Prints; Horses; Military / Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
  - A gymnastics show. 9.2 x 6.5 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Athletes; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Sports
  - A family portrait with two girls. 5.5 x 8.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Arabic Writing; Beards; Egypt; Family Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Hats; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A boy sitting at a desk studying with books. 6.2 x 8.6 cm, 1947; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Books; Boys; Buildings; Egypt; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Reading
  - Ahmed Wali Al Din Series - A man lying down by Aswan Dam, with a camera. 6.2 x 11.0 cm, 2 March 1926; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Arabic Writing; Aswan, Egypt; Cameras; Dams / Barrages; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Nile River; Photographic Prints
  - Ahmed Wali Al Din Series - A man in a classroom with young boys. 6.3 x 8.8 cm, 12 January 1958; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Arabic Writing; Boys; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools / Education; Students; Teachers
  - Ahmed Wali Al Din Series - A young man standing in the desert. 11.6 x 6.9 cm, 3 February 1926; Unknown (Box 4, Folder 24)